# NAUMAN TARIQ

Business Development Manager

0335-4045939 - 0306-1775939



Naumantariq722@gmail.com



Lahore, Pakistan



## **SUMMARY**

A creative, persistent, agile and driven business development manager who is more than able to nurture relationships with existing clients and to develop new business opportunities. I'm an expert at putting together penetrative marketing strategies that can help businesses to fulfill their potential On an individual/team level i'm the one who is committed to my own personal development and progression. I have an enthusiastic approach to direct sales.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Punjab University**

MS MASS COMMUNICATION

#### SKILLS

- Ability to investigate and seek out alternative solutions to problems
- Driving peak performance across all areas of the business
- Able to work closely with Account Management teams in drawing up strategies on how to sell to clients
- Remaining calm under high pressure, and able to meet tight deadlines
- Willing to take ownership and responsibility of all the marketing activities in a company
- Having an in-depth knowledge of computer systems and software relevant to sales and business development
- Developing negotiating strategies for price conscious customers
- Experience in a client facing environment

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

- MEAN MERN
- PYTHON
- BLOCKCHAIN
- METAVERSE
- ELIXIR
- 3D UNITY GAME
- UNREAL ENGINE
- IOS/ANDROID DEVELOPMENT
- SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETING

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

DYCODERS / Collaboration with INVOZONE | Jan 2023 - Present

- Having overall responsibility for achieving weekly KPIs in client
  management, sales and pipeline activity. Also in charge of implementing
  changes to help the company reach its full potential, and of increasing
  businesses market share within existing markets and also successfully
  penetrating new markets
- Conducting professional presentations of new proposals
- Anticipating market trends so that the company keeps and enhances its competitive advantage
- Presenting convincing business and financial arguments to customers
- · Responding quickly and efficiently to all sales enquiries
- Working closely with the company's operations and marketing teams
- Reviewing business plans against actual results and then trying to determine reasons for any deviations

## **TEAM LEAD**

Kryptomind | 2020 - 2022

Responsible to generate new business opportunities through lead
generations via freelance platforms/linked in; industry conferences and
written tender process A large part of my role is to develop and maintain
a great relationship with council committees and to provide them with
suitable solutions to help improve internal processes by providing a
customized demonstration of the system functionalities; on-site training
and aftersale technical support Managed Trivanto full operation in
Australia including New Business Generation, Account management,
aftersale technical support

#### **TEAM LEAD**

CROWNCONCEPTS | 2016 - 2020

- Worked to identify and develop breakthrough technologies that create innovative products for our athletes.
- Adept in working collaboratively with team members to design and execute innovative models that enhance manufacturing initiatives.
- Created and fostered long-lasting partnerships business partnerships that played a key role in company success. Successfully identified emerging trends and leading innovation, leading to successful business developments on our end.